Guide to the Facilities Management Department records, 1990-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Facilities Management Department records 1990-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Facilities Management Department.
1.65 Linear Feet 1750 Items
The Facilities Management Department (FMD) is responsible for the maintenance, repair and minor alteration of the campus facilities.
Collection contains material pertaining to the operations of the Facilities Management Department (FMD) including 1990/1991 annual report, committee minutes, and a current replacement value audit (1991). The main subject present in the collection is the restoration of the Duke Chapel stained glass windows. Materials in the collection date from 1990-ongoing.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Facilities Management Department records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1995-2006, 2008, 2010.
Historical Note
The Facilities Management Department (FMD) is responsible for the maintenance, repair and minor alteration of the campus facilities. FMD employees are ready to respond to urgent or specialized needs, and provide valuable service for basic maintenance and repair programs. They are also able to provide timely and flexible renovation services of moderate scope. FMD has also been known as Facilities Planning and Management.
Collection Overview
Collection contains material pertaining to the operations of the Facilities Management Department (FMD) including 1990/1991 annual report, committee minutes, and a current replacement audit value (1991). However, the main subject present in the collection is the restoration of the Duke Chapel stained glass windows. Each restored window contains a condition report by Dieter Goldkuhle and color slides of the conservation. Rubbings have also been made of the Chapel windows and they are housed in the vault. Also present is a volume with text and photographs that document the Chapel Crypt opening and closing guide in preparation for Terry Sanford's internment. Materials in the collection date from 1990-ongoing.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke Chapel (Durham, N.C.)
Duke University -- Administration.
Duke University. Office of the Executive Vice President
Glass, colored -- Conservation and restoration
Glass painting and staining -- Conservation and restoration
Sanford, Terry, 1917-1998
photographs, color
rubbing (transferring techniques).
color slides
Separated Material
Chapel window rubbings are stored separately in the library stacks. A zip drive containing jpeg images of the restoration of window #212 and #223 were separated and the images were downloaded onto the digital server.
Related Material
Vice President for Administrative Services records, 1980-1992.
University Archives, Duke University.
Work Zone, 2000-2005. [serial].
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 3 Boxes
  - Annual Report, 1990/1991 (Box 1)
  - Banner Committee, 1996 (re: placement of banners on Duke University campus)
  - Current Replacement Value (CRV) Audit, July 1991
  - Restoration slides and report, Ruth and Naomi windows #201 and #202, Duke Chapel, April 1994
  - Restoration slides and report, Adam window #205, Duke Chapel, August 1995 (3 folders)
  - Restoration slides and report, Noah window #206, Duke Chapel, September 2002 (3 folders)
  - Restoration slides and report, Melchezedek window, #207, Duke Chapel, August 2003(3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Restoration slides and report, Abraham window #208, Duke Chapel, August 2004 (3 folders)
  - Restoration slides and report, Isaac window #209, Duke Chapel, August 2006 (3 folders)
  - Restoration slides and report, South-West Transept (Joseph, Gabriel, Mary, Elijah, Elisha, Hezekiah) window #211, Duke Chapel, August 2005 (3 folders)
  - Restoration slides and report, Panel A3 window #227, Duke Chapel, January 2001
  - Restoration slides and report, Tobit window #228, Duke Chapel, September 2000, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Restoration slides and report, Tobit window #228, Duke Chapel, Appendix A, (2 folders)
  - Crypt Opening/Closing Procedure Guide, 1998
  - Restoration Report: Window #212, April 2010
  - Restoration Report: Window #223, April 2011
  - Chapel windows #s 201 (Ruth), 204, 205 (Adam), 228 (Tobit)
  - Noah window, #206
  - Melchezedek window, #207
  - Abraham window, #208
  - Isaac window, #209
  - Rubbing/leading guides Chapel window, #210
  - Panel and Trefoil rubbings/leading guides, #211